Constance Baker Motley papers SSC.MS.00110
Sophia Smith Collection
- Joel Motley collection of Constance Baker Motley papers, 1934-2018; 2018-S-0057; Motley, Constance Baker; Motley, Joel; 4 linear feet 3 record cartons, 1 11x14 OS box, 1 oversize folder.
  - SUBSERIES II: CORRESPONDENCE, 1950-2009
    - Personal correspondence, 1969-2007 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Professional Correspondence, 1950-2002 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Postcards, 1979, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Elena Kagan to Joel Motley, 2008 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Invitations to Constance Baker Motley symposium, 2009 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - The Crisis magazine, June-July 1963 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Israeli Women for Ida Nudel newsletter no. 1, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Invitation to White House luncheon with Lady Bird Johnson, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Change newsletter vol. 1 no. 6, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Trends in Housing newsletter vol. 7, no. 5, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - SUBSERIES III: PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, 1934-1997
    - "Desegregation and Education" by Constance Baker Motley in the Mississippi Law Journal, Fall 1988 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - M.A.A. Time Schedule, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "My Personal Debt to Thurgood Marshall" by Constance Baker Motley in the Yale Law Journal, October 1991 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Election leaflet for New York State Senate race, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Congressional record of the 89th Congress, second session, vol. 112, no. 145, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Various writings, approximately 1963-1967 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Design for the American Negro Reference Book Discussion" draft, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - New York State Department of Law's Civil Rights Bureau's Annual Report, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "The Concept of Identity in Race Relations: Notes and Queries" by Erik. H. Erikson, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "Culture, Class, and the Behavior of Low Income Families" by Hylan Lewis, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Papers relating to the planning session for the White House Conference "To Fulfill These Rights", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Draft of final report from White House planning session, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Court case decisions, 1934-1964 (Box 18, Folder 14-22)
    - Handwritten notes, approximately 1963-1967 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - "The Legal Status of the Negro" typescript, approximately 1963-1967 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Court case transcripts, 1961-1963 (Box 18, Folder 16, 23-25)
    - NAACP booklet "Racial Inequality in Education", approximately 1953-1967 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - American Missionary Association booklet "If Your Next Neighbors are Negros", approximately 1953-1967 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - NAACP Civil Rights handbook, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - "They Represent YOU" pamphlet, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - New York City charter, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Commerce Cleaning House booklet "Civil Rights Act of 1964 with explanation" (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - United States Commission on Civil Rights report "Voting in Mississippi", 1965 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - "The ABCs of the Education Park" pamphlet, approximately 1948-1949 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - NAACP 40th anniversary program, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - NAACP annual report, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Bound legal opinions of Constance Baker Motley, 1977-1997 (Box 19)
  - SUBSERIES IV: SPEECHES, 1963-1992
    - Speech given at Constance Baker Motley portrait unveiling, author unknown (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Constance Baker Motley to New York County Lawyers Annual Bar Dinner, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Joel Motley to International Outlook, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Sisterhood of Temple Israel, no author, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Constance Baker Motley at University of North Carolina Chapel Hill (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Constance Baker Motley to Prince Hall Masons, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "Civil Rights: Significant Recent Legal Developments" by Constance Baker Motley, approximately 1960 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Constance Baker Motley to Triennial Assembly of the United Church Women, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Constance Baker Motley to The Women's City Club of New York, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Constance Baker Motley to the 63rd Convention of the Louisiana Educational Association, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Constance Baker Motley to Message magazine (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Constance Baker Motley, no title (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Constance Baker Motley to the John A. Andrew Clinical Society, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Constance Baker Motley to The Church of the Epiphany, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Handwritten notes for "Life and Liberty" (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - OVERSIZE MATERIALS
    - Portraits: Twentieth Century Americans of Negro Lineage, approximately 1960-1970 (Box 20)
    - Photo of Constance Baker Motley by Lynne Gilbert, approximately 1960-1970 (Box 20)
    - Journal of Pictorial Living, April 11, 1965 (Box 20)
    - Certificate of admission as attorney and counselor, United States Court of Appeals 6th Circuit to Constance Baker Motley, 1955 (Box 20)
    - Columbia University Bachelor of Laws diploma, 1946 (Flat file folder Flat File)
    - Certificate of admission as attorney and counselor, Supreme Court of the United States to Constance Baker Motley, 1952 (Flat file folder Flat File)
    - New Haven High School diploma, 1936 (Flat file folder Flat File)
    - Colgate University Doctor of Civil Law degree, 1987 (Flat file folder Flat File)
    - Courtroom illustration, 1963 (Flat file folder Flat File)
    - Election poster for Manhattan Borough President race, 1964 (Flat file folder Flat File)